Renfei HUANG (黄任飞)

Basic Information

Renfei is currently a first-year Ph.D. student in the **Department of Computer Science and Engineering** at the **Hong Kong University of Science and Technology**. He's supervisor is Prof. QU Huamin
(http://huamin.org). His research interests include Data Visualization, Data Mining, Cloud Computing and Distributed Systems.

Gender: Male

Phone: +86 17816859183 / +852 51489964

Email: rhuangan@ust.hk

Address: HKUST, Clear Water Bay, Kowloon

Education

• Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China

• **B.Eng.**, Computer Science and Engineering, June 2018

• GPA: 3.9 / 4.0 or 88 / 100

• Rank: Top 5%

Standard Tests

• TOEFL iBT Total: 100 R: 29 L: 24 S: 20 W: 27

• GRE Total: 320 Verbal: 151 Quantitative: 169

Research Experiences

• June 2016 till Sept. 2017

 Research Assistant under supervision of Prof. Yunjun GAO (http://mypage.zju.edu.cn/gaoyj cn)

• I implemented a co-movement pattern mining algorithm on Apache Spark based on the system developed in our lab. It's capable of mining massive

trajectory data of taxis with great efficiency. I was acknowledged with my contribution in the paper "Xin Ding, Lu Chen, Yunjun Gao, Christian S. Jensen, and Hujun Bao. UlTraMan: A Unified Platform for Big Trajectory Data Management and Analytics. PVLDB, 11(7): 787-799, 2018.".

- Sept. 2017 till March 2018
- Worked with Prof. Wei WANG and PhD candidate Yinghao YU at HKUST on load balancing in distributed caching systems, such as Alluxio. The paper has been accepted by SC18 as following.
- Yinghao Yu, Renfei Huang, Wei Wang, Jun Zhang, and Khaled B.
 Letaief, "SP-Cache: Load-balanced, Redundancy-free Cluster Caching
 with Selective Partition," to appear in IEEE/ACM International Conference
 for High Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis
 (SC18), Dallas, TX, November, 2018.
- March 2018 till July 2018
- Internship at cpchain.io working on Block chain technology as a core developer and associate researcher.

Awards

- First-Class Scholarship for Elite Students in Basic Science (Top 5% in College of Computer Science, 3 times)
- Second-Class Scholarship for Outstanding Merits (Top 3 in class)
- Huawei PhD Fellowship Scheme (HPFS), 2018.